<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2013-11-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Sinatra Round Two - Group Date</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/posts/2013/11/01/Sinatra-Round-2-Group-Date/"/>
    <id>/posts/2013/11/01/Sinatra-Round-2-Group-Date/</id>
    <published>2013-11-01T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-11-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/two-spacegals.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So for our second round with Sinatra, it was a group date. Four to be
exact. It was a far more valuable experience this
go-around, in that I actually learned AND applied some of my learning! The ole’
synapses finally started to click on day two of the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Highlights include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Area of most growth - definitely testing. Exposure to &amp;lt;a href=
"https://github.com/jnicklas/capybara" target= blank&amp;gt;Capybara&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; and
overall just starting to think with a “test first” mindset. I’m not
quite yet the testing artist I hope to be, but at least I’m able to
think through some ideas on where/how/what to test first when
starting to construct a feature. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Area of most lightbulbs - generally in how things work in
Sinatra, especially around routes and parameters/hashes. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Area of most confusion - setting up the database method and trying to
account for a test db along with a dev db. I would like to spend a
little more time in understanding how best to architect the different
environments and run automated testing across the whole app.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I had another week, I might try to rebuild &amp;lt;a href=
'http://www.aha-method.com/' target= blank&amp;gt;The Aha Method&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; website,
which was something I built a long time ago (with a lot of help). It is
small enough that I think I could tackle it on my own, as well as
enhance the contact feature and the bratblog summary feature (which
currently parses html with a regex, and that is a ‘no-no’). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Team Thoughts - working with Nathaniel, Rolen and Louisa was super
rad. Nathaniel and Rolen were very patient with both Louisa and
myself, as we forced them to sit through our slow typing and
explain the same things at least three times, sometimes using different
accents while also drawing cartoon pictures on the whiteboard.
Additionally, Rolen took on several nicknames, including
“Papa-Rolen”, “The Godfather” and “Ironic Overlord” (rolen.io), aka
&lt;em&gt;Fierce Cat on a Fire Breathing Unicorn&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/rolen-io.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My First Date with Sinatra</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/posts/2013/10/28/My-First-Date-With-Sinatra/"/>
    <id>/posts/2013/10/28/My-First-Date-With-Sinatra/</id>
    <published>2013-10-28T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-10-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sinatra_girl.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first date with &amp;lt;a href= "http://www.sinatrarb.com/" target= blank&amp;gt;Sinatra&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; was a hot mess. And that damn tipped over
rocks glass for error messages is enough to drive a girl to drink. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/rocks-glass.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overly excited about building a web app, due to having some
cursory experience with a little front-end dev, I decided to
approach the Sinatra tutorial with guns a blazin’ and 
follow the tutorial using &amp;lt;a href= "http://haml.info/" target= blank&amp;gt;Haml&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; instead of ERB (short for "Embedded RuBy", not to be confused with "&amp;lt;a href= 'http://www.epicrapbattlesofhistory.com/' target= blank&amp;gt;Epic Rap Battles&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;"). I mean, how hard could
it be? Talk about kicking my own ass… sheesh. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First and foremost,
&amp;lt;a href= "http://tutorials.jumpstartlab.com/projects/idea_box.html"
target= blank&amp;gt;Ideabox&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; introduced the use of forms, which I had zero experience with
and found them to be a tiny beast of weirdness all their own. Then,
layer on top of that translating ERB instructions from the tutorial
real-time into Haml had me and the spilled glass of Jack w/ water
and three ice-cubes (the real &amp;lt;a href= "http://jrcx.wordpress.com/2012/10/04/sinatrajd/" target= blank&amp;gt;Sinatra's poison &amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; of choice) in lock step for the duration of the exercise.
And I’m a vodka girl, so it wasn’t a pleasant experience,
although spilling booze in any context is generally an unpleasant
faux-pas. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So where did I end up? Well… I completed the project, so
there is that, but I certainly wasn’t proud of it and absolutely none
of it was test driven. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did however, learn a lot. And the post exercise where we sat with &amp;lt;a
href= "https://github.com/jcasimir?source=cc" target= blank&amp;gt;Jeff&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
and worked through how to approach testing with Ideabox was hugely
beneficial. That said, I would most definitely repeat the exercise,
with TDD first and foremost, as well hopefully having some time to add
more extensions and make the front-end pretty. Another piece of good
news is that re-writing the views in Haml was an extension, which
I only learned after the fact, which was a nice surprise. This
was the first project since the start of school that I was able to
complete in its entirety with an extension. &lt;strong&gt;Kazaam&lt;/strong&gt;!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the Sinatra shin-dig, we had our first “code retreat” at The
Source in Denver. It was like speed-dating, but with code-pairing.
And it was fantastic! All of my fellow students proved to be much
better dates than Sinatra, if for no other reason than they didn’t keep
spilling liquor on me. I especially enjoyed the &amp;lt;a href=
"http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Groundhog_Day_(film)" target= blank&amp;gt;Groundhog Day&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; approach,
where we kept repeating the same exercise over and over as we changed
pairs. Even though the exercise was the same, the change in pairs
and the application of learning from one session to the next really
changed the dynamic of the exercise. Sometimes - I felt pretty stupid,
but a lot of times, I actually contributed to the process of
writing some code that worked. And that always feels great.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Focus Week Relief</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/posts/2013/10/11/Focus-Week-Relief/"/>
    <id>/posts/2013/10/11/Focus-Week-Relief/</id>
    <published>2013-10-11T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-10-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/woman_couch.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we just finished our first of three focus weeks at the &lt;a href="http://www.gschool.it/" target="blank"&gt;gSchool&lt;/a&gt;, and
it could not have come at a better time – well, except maybe a little
earlier. Seriously - I think I've been desperate for a focus week. A
break in the fierce treading of water that is the daily grind of class
instruction and looming project deliverables, due dates, and
overall feeling of having no idea what the hell I am doing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Focus week was the invitation to pump the brakes and slow down long enough
to ensure we were grounded in the code we were writing. In such that
even if it wasn't a lot of code, it was code we understood. So I
feel better about a lot of the fundamentals, in terms of understanding
how to work with hashes, arrays, strings, methods, and most
importantly, a better understanding of the ruby object model. I'm not
sure I "mastered" anything, or that I even know what that might look
like, but I do feel there was some progression and that I was able to
take a moment to just breathe (insert momentary sigh of relief here). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, we were divided into groups of similar skill level and the
smaller group atmosphere was super &lt;a href="http://www.themovierad.com/#!/Home" target="blank"&gt;RAD&lt;/a&gt;. I don't necessarily think it is required for the full 24 weeks of the
course, but I think it's needed a LOT more. The small group approach
created a dynamic where I actually felt like I was learning &lt;em&gt;with&lt;/em&gt;
people, as opposed to just trying to hang on for dear life to the coat
tails of those who seem light years ahead of me. Whether or not they are in fact light years ahead of me is irrelevant. Perception is reality and as a noob on the Planet of Programming, sometimes this is my reality:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/scream.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also found the small groups were more vocal in class, and I believe that is because we all felt safer with
one another, in that our contributions and questions were useful for
everyone. &lt;br /&gt;
Next week we start web applications. I have no expectations,
other than I would really like to finish the project on time. I assume
it will be hard, but I'm hoping it doesn't feel impossible like
some of the last projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And lastly, even though I feel a little better right now, I know
another big tidal wave is just around the corner, waiting to smash
my noob face into the ground. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bring it. &amp;lt;sigh&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Baby Steps and Novice Love</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/posts/2013/09/27/Baby-Steps-And-Novice-Love/"/>
    <id>/posts/2013/09/27/Baby-Steps-And-Novice-Love/</id>
    <published>2013-09-27T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-09-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="baby" src="/images/baby.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am currently reading a book from the &lt;a href="http://www.gschool.it/" target="blank"&gt;gSchool&lt;/a&gt; reading list called
&lt;a href="http://pragprog.com/book/ahptl/pragmatic-thinking-and-learning" target="blank"&gt;Pragmatic Thinking and Learning: Refactor your Wetware&lt;/a&gt;.
The author, Andy Hunt, dives into how our brains are
wired, and how to apply ourselves in learning new skills. It is written
with programming in mind, but uses examples and analogies that span
other professional and artistic disciplines. Andy claims:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In this book you'll learn how to:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
+ Use the Dreyfus Model of Skill Acquisition to become more expert&lt;br /&gt;
+ Leverage the architecture of the brain to strengthen different thinking modes&lt;br /&gt;
+ Avoid common "known bugs" in your mind&lt;br /&gt;
+ Learn more deliberately and more effectively&lt;br /&gt;
+ Manage knowledge more efficiently  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes please. Sign me up.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am only on chapter three, but actually feeling like there might be hope
for me yet. He talks at length about the Dreyfus model of Skill
Acquistion in the first three chapters. I won't go into detail on the
model, but it's worth investigating further if you are so inclined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I will, however, provide you with
&lt;a href="https://github.com/kytrinyx?source=cc" target="blank"&gt;Katrina's&lt;/a&gt; succinct and apt
summation of the scale, with the following excerpt from her talk on 
&lt;a href="http://kytrinyx.com/blog/hacking-passion" target="blank"&gt;Hacking Passion&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;br /&gt;
+ Novice: where you know nothing&lt;br /&gt;
+ Advanced beginner: where you still suck, but you start seeing what
this might be about&lt;br /&gt;
+ Competent: where you can start getting shit done&lt;br /&gt;
+ Proficient: where you get shit done really well&lt;br /&gt;
+ Expert: where the shit you get done seems like magic to pretty much
everyone else.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a novice. And according to Andy Hunt, those who are of the novice
persuasion require a specific kind of teaching love. Here are a couple
high-level themes from the book that spoke to me personally:  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;First: Crawl, Walk, Run&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In that order. Focus on small conceptual chunks to practice repeatedly.
Inserting appropriate variations that challenge, but are still closely
related to the same concept. This is about building a foundation through
practice, but doing it with baby steps. And, as with toddlers, create an
environment that makes lots of small wins accessible and celebrate them
to create the confidence to move through the stages of crawl, walk, run.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Second: Pressure Kills Cognition.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This notion was actually detailed in chapter seven, but referenced in
chapter three. Simply put, pressure stifles creativity, it shuts down
the areas of our brain we should be accessing religiously while we
learn, in favor of a fight or flight instinct resulting from the terror
of failing to deliver. I especially had a lot of that going on for the
first three weeks of gSchool. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These chapters really got me thinking about the particular
needs and state of mind of the novice. Mind you, it is never a
one-size-fits-all declaration, but I can attest that some of us in
school are of the particular novice persuasion who would respond better,
and grow faster, with just a few extras bolted onto the first few weeks
of school. Ideas include:&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
 + &lt;strong&gt;Study Hall&lt;/strong&gt;. An hour or so, 2-3 times per week, before or after class
   to focus on the fundamentals. To revisit again and again the concepts
   and problems presented in class that are escaping us.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 + &lt;strong&gt;Mentors at the Start&lt;/strong&gt;. If it were possible to introduce a few mentors
   at the start of the program, this would be amazing. Sometimes, we
   masochistic novices struggle too long and too hard, to the point of
   total breakdown, and having additional resources who were available
   more frequently, especially in the off-hours, could really make the
   difference in our ability to jump the big hurdles and gain much needed
   confidence.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 + &lt;strong&gt;Baby Step Tutorials&lt;/strong&gt;. Smaller chunks of learning exercises
   that force us to repeat the little things and apply them
   progressively, in a building block format.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 + &lt;strong&gt;Invitation to Pace&lt;/strong&gt;. This, for me, is critical. While it is true we
   don't receive traditional grades in gSchool, I spent the first three
   weeks beating myself up because I couldn't finish everything, and the
   first project, I can't even say I really started. And I was beginning
   to lose faith in the process, and even worse, myself. And I found the
   messages around the importance of finishing the first few projects to
   be rather inconsistent. And it was hard to prioritize what I should
   be focused on in order to avoid being left behind, or miss something
   critical to my success. Might seem trivial in hindsight, but as a
   noob, I don't know what I don't know, and even the little things get
   overwhelming.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
 + &lt;strong&gt;More Pictures&lt;/strong&gt;. The diagrams and the whiteboards help a lot. Even when
   its just writing code on the wall with markers, it is wonderful. I
   think this is because it forces everyone to slow down. For the novice
   crew, sometimes we find ourselves struggling to just keep up with all
   the window hopping and fast code typing on the screen during class
   instruction and that often causes unintended consequences of not
   really listening (because we are panicked about keeping up), or just
   checking out because we miss one step and suddenly find ourselves in
   no-man's land without a clue as to what question to even ask.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That's all I got for right now. I only read three chapters, however
Katrina contributed a very thorough analysis on the Jumpstart Blog &lt;a href="http://jumpstartlab.com/news/archives/2013/10/03/pragmatic-learning-at-gschool-part-i" target="blank"&gt;Jumpstart Blog&lt;/a&gt; , so you should definitely check it out. There will be more to come as we
finish the book over the next couple weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the best part about reading this book, is that gSchool is reading it
with me. And most importantly, they are switching gears in some of the
areas listed above in order to make me successful. There is no question
this is the right place for learning to program and they are the best at
what they do (and because they listen and care, my desire to punch them
in the nose on a couple early occasions was only fleeting). &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>I have No Idea What I Am Doing</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/posts/2013/09/20/I-Have-No-Idea-What-I-Am-Doing/"/>
    <id>/posts/2013/09/20/I-Have-No-Idea-What-I-Am-Doing/</id>
    <published>2013-09-20T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-09-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/woman_computer.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to insert ERB tags into haml.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got myself up "git creek" when I thought it would be cool to rebase. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I lost hours googling my googles because I didn't understand the
answers to my noob questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have yet to fully complete an in-class exercise during the allocated
class time @ the &lt;a href="http://www.gschool.it/" target="blank"&gt;gSchool&lt;/a&gt;   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote eight lines of code for Event Reporter (first "real" project
assigned with a one week turn time.) and none of them did
anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent an hour and a half relentlessly trying to debug a functional
file that wasn't even the file I was requiring in the test suite I was
working from - seriously. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never use the damn Pomodoro, even though I know I should, and my psyche suffers for it after I have spent a ridiculous number of hours straight looking at my monitor with no break. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have no idea what I am doing. And some of these things are just plain
hysterical. I'll get there. Just keep swimming…&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Desperately Seeking Noob Status</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/posts/2013/09/13/Desperately-Seeking-Noob-Status/"/>
    <id>/posts/2013/09/13/Desperately-Seeking-Noob-Status/</id>
    <published>2013-09-13T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-09-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="noob-nerd" src="/images/noob-nerd.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the start of my learning to program adventure, my mentor referred to
me as a noob in an email exchange. I made the mistake of
correcting his spelling, assuming he must have meant newb, as in newbie,
one "new" to a particular practice or profession. I even sent him an urban dictionary
link as added support and humorous reference material. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His response: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wow. Just wow. You just solidified your "noob" status majorly. First off
only dumb marketing people use the term "newb" and then go on to
actually quote something from Urban Dictionary. Seriously, you are
quoting "Urban Dictionary"? It's so lame I won't even click on the link.
You're "noob" status just hit a whole new level. I'm not even sure there
is a term for it. And by the way, if you were a gamer (which obviously
you are not), you would be referred to as "n00b". That's right double
zero style. This is fucking unbelievable.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Huh. So apparently I was already way behind in this whole programming
thing and I hadn't even started? Hello Humble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned a lot from my mentor over the next several months, his bark
being infinitely more worse than his bite, and came to the quick
realization that once-a-week-instruction, with some practice in the
evenings after my day job, was not going to cut it. I needed to find a way
to do this full time, because I was hooked and desperately seeking noob
status - for real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter the opportunity at &lt;a href="http://www.gschool.it" target="blank"&gt;gSchool&lt;/a&gt;. I applied, I stalked the founder, and
I was a mild train wreck at the interview, which all combined, magically resulted
in my acceptance (because apparently they don't read your writing
sample). And so began my noob life. In week one, or rather week zero,
they started us off with an initiation in improv, Ruby in 100 minutes and a
tidal wave of tutorials to prep us for the deep end of the ocean, which
is weird, because I was pretty sure I was already in the deep end of the
ocean when I quit my career (marketing of course) of 10 years so I could learn to code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A small handful of highlights from the week:&lt;br /&gt;
+  string manipulation&lt;br /&gt;
+  using ERB for templating&lt;br /&gt;
+  reading data from CSV files&lt;br /&gt;
+  rotating arrays&lt;br /&gt;
+  zipping hashes&lt;br /&gt;
+  middleman blog creation&lt;br /&gt;
+  installing and using gems&lt;br /&gt;
+  setting up programming environment&lt;br /&gt;
+  conditional branching and looping  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while I would love to expound on all of the above, or even provide
the full list of topics covered in week zero, there is just no
fucking way. I am buried. Or to keep with the ocean metaphor,
drowning. I never expected this noob life to be easy, but right now, I
am just hoping I can actually keep swimming for the next six months.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
